<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<book id="book" lang="de">
  <bookinfo>
    <title>Book</title>
    <releaseinfo role="CVS">
    </releaseinfo>
    <authorgroup>
      <corpauthor>
      </corpauthor>
      <author>
        <firstname>me</firstname>
        <surname>me.last</surname>
        <affiliation>
          <address>
            <email>name@unknown.com</email>
          </address>
        </affiliation>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
    <copyright>
      <holder>unknown GmbH</holder>
    </copyright>
    <pubdate>
    </pubdate>
    <abstract>
      <para>
      </para>
    </abstract>
  </bookinfo>
  <part>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
Gestaltlupe is a scientific tool to render tomographic functions. 
A tomographic function <emphasis branch="">T(p)</emphasis> (<emphasis branch="">p</emphasis> is a point <emphasis branch="">p=(x,y,z)</emphasis> in <emphasis branch="">R^3</emphasis>) returns either <emphasis branch="">true</emphasis> or <emphasis branch="">false</emphasis>. The rendering 
interpreted this as formula description of an arbitrary object in the 3D space. This means: <emphasis branch="">T(p)=true</emphasis>, 
if and only if <emphasis branch="">p</emphasis> is inside the object. </para>
    <para>
Double click on <application branch="">Gestaltlupe_1_0_2.exe</application> , choose Tab <emphasis branch="">file</emphasis>, load an sample project and press the 
button “preview” to get after a short time a small picture of the given 3D object, or press "start" 
to render a bitmap in full resolution. </para>
  </part>
  <part>
    <title>Install
</title>
    <para>Gestaltlupe is available at GitHub at:

<ulink url="" branch="">http://github.com/trafassel/Gestaltlupe </ulink>
   
The corresponding Version 1.0.2, which is documented here, can be found at:

<ulink url="" branch="">http://github.com/trafassel/Gestaltlupe/blob/master/bin/Gestaltlupe_1_0_2.exe </ulink>

On this page you have to click “raw” to get the binary.  But the recommended way to work with 
Gestaltlupe is to download the full archive file (the big “Download” button at 
<ulink url="" branch="">http://github.com/trafassel/Gestaltlupe </ulink>). The archive contains the binaries and sample projects 
with the corresponding formulas.
</para>
    <para />
    <chapter>
      <title>Windows</title>
      <para>
Gestaltlupe is developed and tested with WindowsXP and Windows7. It is a native .NET 2.0 application. </para>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
      <title>Linux
</title>
      <para>To run Gestaltlupe  on a Linux system, you have to install the mono package 
(<ulink url="" branch="">http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page </ulink>). It is tested on a Ubuntu Hardy Heron 8.04.3 LTS. 
It runs without problems, but looks more ugly than the windows version (Yes, that is possible).</para>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
      <title>Mac OSX</title>
      <para>
It is tested on a Mac OSX 10.6. with Mono 2.8 . It can produce some nice pictures, but working is a 
pain, because some windows forms are not redrawn properly (Gestaltlupe is compatible to the 
Windows.Forms library 2.0).</para>
    </chapter>
  </part>
  <part>
    <title>Interface Description
</title>
    <para>After its first start, Gestaltlupe presents the following interface.</para>
    <imageobject>
      <title>Start Screen</title>
      <imagedata format="png" fileref="pic/start.png" />
    </imageobject>
    <para>If you click on the left square in the bottom frame, you get a small overview of the defined scene. </para>
    <imageobject>
      <title>
      </title>
      <imagedata format="png" fileref="pic/firstPic.png" />
    </imageobject>
    <para>If the view looks OK, you can click on <emphasis branch="">Preview</emphasis> to get a greater picture. The result ist presented in the output window.</para>
    <imageobject>
      <title>
      </title>
      <imagedata format="png" fileref="pic/FirstPreview.png" />
    </imageobject>
    <para>The picture is saved automatic. The corresponding path is given at the top of the output window.</para>
    <para>The final rendering starts after click on the button <emphasis branch="">Start</emphasis>.</para>
    <imageobject>
      <title>
      </title>
      <imagedata format="png" fileref="pic/firstRendering.png" />
    </imageobject>
    <para>Are you satisfied with the result? Not, oh, ...</para>
    <para>If you want to improve the quality of the rendering result, you have the read the chapter Rendering.</para>
    <para>Or perhaps you want to see, what is inside the tunnel or you want to rotate and zoom the whole object.
The chapter Navigation describes, how to navigate in the virtual 3D space.</para>
    <para>I understand. You favourite formula is another fractal, and you want to have some colours. Then you have to read the chapter Formula.  </para>
    <chapter>
      <title>Rendering</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
      <title>Navigation</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
      <title>Formula</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </chapter>
  </part>
</book>